<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/time#"
        xmlns:tzont="http://www.w3.org/2006/timezone#"
        xmlns:tl="http://purl.org/NET/c4dm/timeline.owl#"
        xmlns:geo-pos="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
        xmlns:umbel-ac="http://umbel.org/umbel/ac/"
        xmlns:time="http://www.w3.org/2006/time#"
        xmlns:sw-vocab="http://www.w3.org/2003/06/sw-vocab-status/ns#"
        xmlns:ff="http://factforge.net/"
        xmlns:olo="http://purl.org/ontology/olo/core#"
        xmlns:music-ont="http://purl.org/ontology/mo/"
        xmlns:event="http://purl.org/NET/c4dm/event.owl#"
        xmlns:dc-term="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
        xmlns:om="http://www.ontotext.com/owlim/"
        xmlns:opencyc-en="http://sw.opencyc.org/2008/06/10/concept/en/"
        xmlns:factbook="http://www.daml.org/2001/12/factbook/factbook-ont#"
        xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
        xmlns:pext="http://proton.semanticweb.org/protonext#"
        xmlns:ot="http://www.ontotext.com/"
        xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
        xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
        xmlns:yago="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/"
        xmlns:stories="http://purl.org/ontology/stories/"
        xmlns:umbel="http://umbel.org/umbel#"
        xmlns:pkm="http://proton.semanticweb.org/protonkm#"
        xmlns:wordnet16="http://xmlns.com/wordnet/1.6/"
        xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
        xmlns:po="http://purl.org/ontology/po/"
        xmlns:gr="http://purl.org/goodrelations/v1#"
        xmlns:wordnet="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/"
        xmlns:opencyc="http://sw.opencyc.org/concept/"
        xmlns:wordn-sc="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/schema/"
        xmlns:nytimes="http://data.nytimes.com/"
        xmlns:dbp-prop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
        xmlns:geonames="http://sws.geonames.org/"
        xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
        xmlns:dbpedia="http://dbpedia.org/resource/"
        xmlns:oasis="http://psi.oasis-open.org/iso/639/#"
        xmlns:geo-ont="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#"
        xmlns:umbel-en="http://umbel.org/umbel/ne/wikipedia/"
        xmlns:ptop="http://proton.semanticweb.org/protontop#"
        xmlns:lingvoj="http://www.lingvoj.org/ontology#"
        xmlns:pns="http://data.press.net/ontology/stuff/"
        xmlns:pnt="http://data.press.net/ontology/tag/"
        xmlns:fb="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/"
        xmlns:dbtune="http://dbtune.org/bbc/peel/work/"
        xmlns:psys="http://proton.semanticweb.org/protonsys#"
        xmlns:umbel-sc="http://umbel.org/umbel/sc/"
        xmlns:pni="http://data.press.net/ontology/identifier/"
        xmlns:dbp-ont="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
        xmlns:ub="http://www.lehigh.edu/~zhp2/2004/0401/univ-bench.owl#"
        xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#"
        xmlns:pnc="http://data.press.net/ontology/classification/"
        xmlns:pne="http://data.press.net/ontology/event/"
        xmlns:rel="http://purl.org/vocab/relationship"
        xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#"
        xmlns:pna="http://data.press.net/ontology/asset/">

<rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London_Heathrow_Airport">
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Place"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Place"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Location_Underspecified"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/YagoGeoEntity"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/ArchitecturalStructure"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Building"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Infrastructure"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Airport"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/TransportProjectsInLondon"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Airport"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PuBlicInquiries"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/VisitorAttractionsInHillingdon"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Airport_Physical"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#SpatialThing"/>
        <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://data.press.net/ontology/tag/Tag"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Διεθνές_Αεροδρόμιο_Χίθροου"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Letiště_London_Heathrow"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/London_Heathrow_Airport"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Хитроу"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://linkedgeodata.org/triplify/node26608538"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Aéroport_de_Londres_Heathrow"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Aeroporto_di_Londra-Heathrow"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/런던_히드로_공항"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Port_lotniczy_Londyn-Heathrow"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.03jn4"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ロンドン・ヒースロー空港"/>
        <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Aeroporto_de_Londres_Heathrow"/>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">London Heathrow Airport on Lontoon ja koko Ison-Britannian suurin kansainvälinen lentoasema. Asema sijaitsee Hillingdonin kaupunkipiirissä, 24 kilometriä Lontoon keskustasta länteen. Heathrow on matkustajamääriltään maailman kolmanneksi vilkkain lentoasema ja ulkomaanlennoiltaan maailman vilkkain. Heathrow’n omistaa espanjalaisen Grupo Ferrovialin omistama BAA plc (entinen British Airports Authority).</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">O Aeroporto de Londres Heathrow, também conhecido como Aeroporto de Heathrow, está localizado a oeste de da cidade de Londres, no do Reino Unido. O Aeroporto de Heathrow é o terceiro mais movimentado do mundo a seguir ao Aeroporto Internacional de Atlanta e ao Aeroporto Internacional O'Hare, de Chicago e é o maior aeroporto do mundo em termos de tráfego de passageiros internacionais.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">London-Heathrow flygplats eller Heathrow, är Europas största och världens 3:e största flygplats räknat i antal passagerare per år. 2011 passerade över 69.4 miljoner passagerare flygplatsen. Heathrow byggdes ursprungligen som en bas för det brittiska bombflyget, men öppnade för civil trafik 1946. Fram till 1976 hade flygplatsen det officiella namnet London Airport. Heathrow är hemmabas för British Airways och BMI. En femte terminal öppnade den 14 mars 2008.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ロンドン・ヒースロー空港（ロンドン・ヒースローくうこう、Heathrow Airport）はロンドンの西部にあるイギリス最大規模の空港で、国際線利用者数では世界一の空港である。所有・運営は、民間会社のイギリス空港会社 (BAA) である。空港コードはLHR (IATA) ／EGLL (ICAO) 。ブリティッシュ・エアウェイズ、ヴァージン・アトランティック航空とbmiのハブ空港になっている。</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Letiště Heathrow (London Heathrow Airport) je letiště sídlící na západě Londýna, v městské části Hillingdon. Název nese podle osady Heathrow, která byla roku 1944 kvůli výstavbě letiště srovnána se zemí. Heathrow je podle počtu odbavených cestujících nejvytíženější letiště v Evropě, po letištích Hartsfield-Jackson v Atlantě a O'Hare v Chicagu třetí na světě; díky velkému počtu zahraničních letů je ale podle počtu odbavených zahraničních cestujících největší na světě.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">L'Aeroporto di Londra Heathrow è l'aeroporto principale di Londra. È l'aeroporto più trafficato dell'Unione Europea per numero di passeggeri (e terzo al mondo dopo quelli di Atlanta e Pechino) ed il terzo, nell'UE, per numero di movimenti aerei preceduto da Parigi-Charles de Gaulle e Francoforte; grazie al numero di voli internazionali, è l'aeroporto con il più alto numero di movimenti di passeggeri di voli internazionali.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Der London Heathrow Airport ist der größte der fünf internationalen Verkehrsflughäfen der britischen Hauptstadt London. Er ist mit über 69 Millionen Passagieren im Jahr 2011 der größte Flughafen Europas sowie nach Atlanta und Peking der drittgrößte weltweit . Heathrow dient als Drehkreuz für British Airways, bmi und Virgin Atlantic.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Sân bay London Heathrow, được gọi là Heathrow, là sân bay quốc tế tại thủ đô London, là sân bay nhộn nhịp thứ 3 thế giới năm 2005, xếp sau Sân bay Quốc tế Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta và Sân bay Chicago O'Hare. Heathrow, tuy nhiên, phục vụ nhiều khách quốc tế hơn bất kỳ sân bay nào khác. Heathrow là sân bay nhộn nhịp nhất Vương quốc Anh, lớn nhất châu Âu. Sân bay tọa lạc cách Charing Cross 24 km đông Trung tâm London.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">L'Aeroport de Londres-Heathrow està localitzat al barri de Hillingdon, en els suburbis de l'oest de Londres. Aquest és el tercer aeroport més ocupat del món en tràfic de passatgers, després de l'Aeroport Internacional Hartsfield-Jackson d'Atlanta, l'Aeroport Internacional de Pequín i de l'Aeroport Internacional O'Hare de Chicago, segons estadístiques de l'any 2010.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Heathrow lufthavn, oftest omtalt kun som Heathrow, er Londons største lufthavn, og den travleste lufthavna i Storbritannia. Den ligger i Hillingdon, som er Londons vestligste bydel. På verdensbasis er Heathrow den tredje travleste i totalt antall passasjerer, men på grunn av det store antallet mellomlandinger har den det høyeste antall internasjonale passasjerforflytninger.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">倫敦希斯路機場（英语：London Heathrow Airport，IATA：LHR；ICAO：EGLL），通常簡稱為希斯路機場，位於英國英格蘭大倫敦希靈登區，離倫敦中心有15英里（24千米）遠。此機場由BAA負責營運，為英國航空和維珍航空的樞紐機場以及英伦航空的主要機場，為倫敦最主要的聯外機場，也是全英國乃至全世界最繁忙的機場之一，在全球眾多機場中排行第三，次於美國的亞特蘭大機場和中国的北京首都国际机场。由於機場開出眾多的跨境航班，因此以跨境的客量計算，希斯路機場的客流量是最高的。截至2004年，希斯路機場是全歐洲最繁忙的機場，比巴黎戴高樂機場及法蘭克福國際機場的客量還要高出31.5%，但航班數目則比該兩個機場的總和少三分之一。 希斯路機場擁有兩條平行的東西向跑道及五座航廈。第5航廈已經於2008年3月27日啟用，屆時英航將獨自使用該航廈，而其它航空公司亦會更改所在航廈。</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">런던 히드로 공항은 영국 런던에 있는 국제공항이다.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Port lotniczy Londyn-Heathrow – największy port lotniczy Europy. Położony jest 24 km na zachód od centrum Londynu. Port lotniczy Heathrow w 2005 obsłużył prawie 68 mln pasażerów, co uplasowało go na trzecim miejscu na świecie pod względem ruchu pasażerskiego, po portach lotniczych Chicago-O'Hare i Atlanta – Hartsfield-Jackson.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Аеропорт Хітроу або Гітроу, — найбільший міжнародний аеропорт Великобританії та Європи. За кількістю щорічно перевезених пасажирів - 66 млн. (2009) є третім в світі, після аеропортів Атланти та Чикаго. В Європі за цим покажчиком випереджає аеропорти Париж-Шарль-де-Голль (58 млн. , 2009) та Франкфурт-на-Майні (50,9 млн. , 2009) Має дві розташовані паралельно злітно-посадкові смуги, 5 пасажирських терміналів і вантажний термінал. Знаходиться на віддалі 22 км на захід від Лондона.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L'aéroport de Londres Heathrow est situé dans la banlieue ouest de Londres au Royaume-Uni. C'est le quatrième aéroport mondial en termes de trafic de passagers, avec environ 65,9 millions qui y ont transité en 2010. Il est le premier aéroport d'Europe en termes de passagers et il est le premier aéroport mondial pour le trafic international, avec plus de 63 millions de passagers internationaux pour les douze mois précédant le 31 mai 2011.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">London Heathrow Airport or Heathrow is a major airport serving London, England, United Kingdom. Located in the London Borough of Hillingdon, in West London, Heathrow is the busiest airport in the United Kingdom and the third busiest airport in the world (as of 2011) in terms of total passenger traffic, handling more international passengers than any other airport around the globe.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">A London-Heathrow-i repülőtér vagy csak röviden Heathrow London-ban fekszik, az Egyesült Királyság elsődleges és legfontosabb repülőtere. Utasforgalmat tekintve a világ legforgalmasabb repülőtere, több nemzetközi vonalat irányít, mint a világ bármely más repülőtere. Heathrow a BAA tulajdonában van, ez a cég is irányítja. Ezen kívül a cég még hat repteret irányít/tulajdonol az ország területén, saját maga pedig a spanyol Ferrovial tulajdona.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Хи́троу — крупнейший международный аэропорт Лондона. Считается третьим по загруженности пассажирским аэропортом в мире (2011 год), и первым в Европе. Расположен в 24 км (15 милях) к западу от центрального Лондона. Включает 5 пассажирских терминалов и один грузовой. Последний, 5-й терминал, открыт 14 марта 2008 года королевой Елизаветой II, с 11 апреля 2008 закрывался по техническим причинам до июня 2008 года.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">London Heathrow Airport is het grootste vliegveld van Europa en zodoende ook van Groot-Brittannië. Tevens is dit het vliegveld met de meeste verbindingen naar andere vliegvelden. Op wereldniveau is dit in 2011 het vierde vliegveld in termen van afgehandelde personen, na Atlanta/Hartsfield, Peking/Capital en Chicago/O'Hare. Maar door het grote aantal internationale verbindingen, heeft Heathrow 's werelds grootste aantal internationale passagiersafhandelingen.</rdfs:comment>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="fi">Heathrow'n lentoasema</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">倫敦希斯路機場</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="it">Aeroporto di Londra-Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Letiště London Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="ko">런던 히드로 공항</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="sv">London-Heathrow flygplats</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Sân bay London Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="ja">ロンドン・ヒースロー空港</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="hu">London-Heathrow-i repülőtér</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Place Name</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="pl">Port lotniczy Londyn-Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="nl">Luchthaven Londen Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Хітроу</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="ru">Хитроу</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="no">London Heathrow lufthavn</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="pt">Aeroporto de Londres Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">London Heathrow Airport</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="fr">Aéroport de Londres Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Aeroport de Londres-Heathrow</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Aeropuerto_de_Londres-Heathrow"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:BAA_Limited"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:London_Heathrow_Airport"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Airports_in_the_London_region"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Airports_established_in_1929"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Transport_projects_in_London"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Public_inquiries_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Buildings_and_structures_in_Hillingdon"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Visitor_attractions_in_Hillingdon"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Transport_in_Hillingdon"/>
        <dc-term:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:M4_corridor"/>
        <wasDerivedFrom xmlns="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#" rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Heathrow_Airport?oldid=495283228"/>
        <geo-pos:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-0.461389</geo-pos:long>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.heathrowairport.com/"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.airtimetv.co.uk/"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.hounslowlibraries.org/"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://web.archive.org/web/20080418062038/www.thisislongford.com/heathrow.htm"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.heathrowairport.com"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.lhr-acc.org/"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.archive.org/details/london_airport_TNA"/>
        <dbp-ont:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.heathrowairwatch.org.uk/"/>
        <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.heathrowairport.com/"/>
        <foaf:name xml:lang="en">London Heathrow Airport</foaf:name>
        <dbp-prop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_airport"/>
        <point xmlns="http://www.georss.org/georss/" xml:lang="en">51.4775 -0.4613888888888889</point>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="ja">ロンドン・ヒースロー空港（ロンドン・ヒースローくうこう、Heathrow Airport）はロンドンの西部にあるイギリス最大規模の空港で、国際線利用者数では世界一の空港である。所有・運営は、民間会社のイギリス空港会社 (BAA) である。空港コードはLHR (IATA) ／EGLL (ICAO) 。ブリティッシュ・エアウェイズ、ヴァージン・アトランティック航空とbmiのハブ空港になっている。</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="sv">London-Heathrow flygplats eller Heathrow, är Europas största och världens 3:e största flygplats räknat i antal passagerare per år. 2011 passerade över 69.4 miljoner passagerare flygplatsen. Heathrow byggdes ursprungligen som en bas för det brittiska bombflyget, men öppnade för civil trafik 1946. Fram till 1976 hade flygplatsen det officiella namnet London Airport. Heathrow är hemmabas för British Airways och BMI. En femte terminal öppnade den 14 mars 2008. Trots omfattande förberedelser blev invigningen ett fiasko med hundratals försvunna väskor, som till slut fick skickas till Milano med bil för vidare leverans med expressfirma till ägarna. British Airways anseende skadades allvarligt av denna kris. Flygplatsen har bara två landningsbanor trots den stora trafikmängden, vilket är ett hinder för trafiken. Ett försenat plan har svårt att få ny landningstid. Det finns planer att bygga en tredje bana, men inget beslut är taget. Det finns protester till exempel från de som bor under dess tänkta flygväg.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="uk">Аеропорт Хітроу або Гітроу, — найбільший міжнародний аеропорт Великобританії та Європи. За кількістю щорічно перевезених пасажирів - 66 млн. (2009) є третім в світі, після аеропортів Атланти та Чикаго. В Європі за цим покажчиком випереджає аеропорти Париж-Шарль-де-Голль (58 млн. , 2009) та Франкфурт-на-Майні (50,9 млн. , 2009) Має дві розташовані паралельно злітно-посадкові смуги, 5 пасажирських терміналів і вантажний термінал. Знаходиться на віддалі 22 км на захід від Лондона. Є місцем розташування штаб-квартир британських авікомпаній British Airways та Virgin Atlantic Airways.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="cs">Letiště Heathrow (London Heathrow Airport) je letiště sídlící na západě Londýna, v městské části Hillingdon. Název nese podle osady Heathrow, která byla roku 1944 kvůli výstavbě letiště srovnána se zemí. Heathrow je podle počtu odbavených cestujících nejvytíženější letiště v Evropě, po letištích Hartsfield-Jackson v Atlantě a O'Hare v Chicagu třetí na světě; díky velkému počtu zahraničních letů je ale podle počtu odbavených zahraničních cestujících největší na světě.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="de">Der London Heathrow Airport ist der größte der fünf internationalen Verkehrsflughäfen der britischen Hauptstadt London. Er ist mit über 69 Millionen Passagieren im Jahr 2011 der größte Flughafen Europas sowie nach Atlanta und Peking der drittgrößte weltweit . Heathrow dient als Drehkreuz für British Airways, bmi und Virgin Atlantic.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="no">Heathrow lufthavn, oftest omtalt kun som Heathrow, er Londons største lufthavn, og den travleste lufthavna i Storbritannia. Den ligger i Hillingdon, som er Londons vestligste bydel. På verdensbasis er Heathrow den tredje travleste i totalt antall passasjerer, men på grunn av det store antallet mellomlandinger har den det høyeste antall internasjonale passasjerforflytninger. I Europeisk sammenheng var Heathrow i 2004 verdensdelens travleste lufthavn i antall passasjerer, og tredje travlest i antall fly som lettet og landet.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="zh">倫敦希斯路機場（英语：London Heathrow Airport，IATA：LHR；ICAO：EGLL），通常簡稱為希斯路機場，位於英國英格蘭大倫敦希靈登區，離倫敦中心有15英里（24千米）遠。此機場由BAA負責營運，為英國航空和維珍航空的樞紐機場以及英伦航空的主要機場，為倫敦最主要的聯外機場，也是全英國乃至全世界最繁忙的機場之一，在全球眾多機場中排行第三，次於美國的亞特蘭大機場和中国的北京首都国际机场。由於機場開出眾多的跨境航班，因此以跨境的客量計算，希斯路機場的客流量是最高的。截至2004年，希斯路機場是全歐洲最繁忙的機場，比巴黎戴高樂機場及法蘭克福國際機場的客量還要高出31.5%，但航班數目則比該兩個機場的總和少三分之一。 希斯路機場擁有兩條平行的東西向跑道及五座航廈。第5航廈已經於2008年3月27日啟用，屆時英航將獨自使用該航廈，而其它航空公司亦會更改所在航廈。</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="hu">A London-Heathrow-i repülőtér vagy csak röviden Heathrow London-ban fekszik, az Egyesült Királyság elsődleges és legfontosabb repülőtere. Utasforgalmat tekintve a világ legforgalmasabb repülőtere, több nemzetközi vonalat irányít, mint a világ bármely más repülőtere. Heathrow a BAA tulajdonában van, ez a cég is irányítja. Ezen kívül a cég még hat repteret irányít/tulajdonol az ország területén, saját maga pedig a spanyol Ferrovial tulajdona. Heathrow a British Airways és a Virgin Atlantic Airways központja, és fontos légikikötő a BMI szempontjából is. London központjától 25 km-re nyugatra fekszik. Heathrow-nak két párhuzamos kifutópályája és öt terminálja van. Területe 12,4 km². A Terminal 5-öt II. Erzsébet hivatalosan 2008. március 24-én nyitotta meg, s 27-e óta látogatható az utazóközönség részéről is. A Terminal 2-t és a Queen's Buildinget kiváltó Heathrow East építése a tervek szerint 2008 novemberében kezdődik el, és 2012-re fejeződik be. Ezalatt a Terminal 3-at és 4-et átrendezik. 2007 novemberében tárgyalások kezdődtek egy újabb, harmadik kifutópálya helyéről. A Heathrow-i repülőtérnek olyan hatósági engedélye van, melynek alapján mind utasszállító, mind oktató gépek indítására és érkeztetésére alkalmas.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="nl">London Heathrow Airport is het grootste vliegveld van Europa en zodoende ook van Groot-Brittannië. Tevens is dit het vliegveld met de meeste verbindingen naar andere vliegvelden. Op wereldniveau is dit in 2011 het vierde vliegveld in termen van afgehandelde personen, na Atlanta/Hartsfield, Peking/Capital en Chicago/O'Hare. Maar door het grote aantal internationale verbindingen, heeft Heathrow 's werelds grootste aantal internationale passagiersafhandelingen. Het is de thuisbasis van de Britse maatschappijen bmi, British Airways en Virgin Atlantic Airways. In 2006 was Heathrow het drukste vliegveld van Europa gezien de hoeveelheid passagiers (18,8% meer passagiers dan Luchthaven Charles de Gaulle in Parijs en 27,9% meer dan Luchthaven Frankfurt am Main), maar het stond derde, achter Charles de Gaulle en Frankfurt gezien het aantal vliegbewegingen (11,9% minder landingen en starts dan Charles de Gaulle, en 2,5% minder dan Frankfurt). Heathrow was vierde in het lijstje van vrachtvervoer (36,9% minder vracht dan Charles de Gaulle, 36,8% minder dan Frankfurt, en 14,2% minder dan Luchthaven Schiphol). Heathrow verwerkt in 2011 dagelijks tussen de 1200 en 1300 vluchten, wat uitkomt op een totaal van bijna een half miljoen landende en vertrekkende vliegtuigen per jaar. Terminals 3, 4 en 5 kunnen de Airbus A380 bedienen. Emirates, Singapore Airlines en Qantas vliegen geregeld met een Airbus A380 naar Londen Heathrow.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="ca">L'Aeroport de Londres-Heathrow està localitzat al barri de Hillingdon, en els suburbis de l'oest de Londres. Aquest és el tercer aeroport més ocupat del món en tràfic de passatgers, després de l'Aeroport Internacional Hartsfield-Jackson d'Atlanta, l'Aeroport Internacional de Pequín i de l'Aeroport Internacional O'Hare de Chicago, segons estadístiques de l'any 2010. És el primer aeroport d'Europa en termes de passatgers i és el primer aeroport del món pel que fa al trànsit internacional, amb prop de 60 milions de passatgers internacionals durant el 2009. Pel que fa al nombre d'operacions, l'aeroport ocupa el 12è lloc en el rànquing mundial, amb 466.393 enlairaments i aterratges (2009), però ocupant el segon lloc a Europa per darrere de París-Charles de Gaulle. És un dels cinc aeroports internacionals de l'àrea metropolitana de la ciutat de Londres i és gestionat per BAA Limited que, a part de Heathrow, també s'encarrega de cinc aeroports més del Regne Unit. L'aeroport de Londres-Heathrow és també el principal centre de connexions de diverses aerolínies britàniques com és el cas de British Airways, Virgin Atlantic o British Midland Airways.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="pl">Port lotniczy Londyn-Heathrow – największy port lotniczy Europy. Położony jest 24 km na zachód od centrum Londynu. Port lotniczy Heathrow w 2005 obsłużył prawie 68 mln pasażerów, co uplasowało go na trzecim miejscu na świecie pod względem ruchu pasażerskiego, po portach lotniczych Chicago-O'Hare i Atlanta – Hartsfield-Jackson. W Europie port lotniczy zajmuje pierwsze miejsce pod względem liczby pasażerów, trzecie pod względem liczby operacji lotniczych i czwarte pod względem ilości przeładowanych towarów (2005). Port zajmuje pierwsze miejsce na świecie pod względem liczby obsługiwanych pasażerów w ruchu międzynarodowym. Port lotniczy posiada 5 terminali lotniczych. Planuje się także budowę trzeciego pasa startowego, obok istniejących równoległych pasów usytuowanych w kierunku wschód-zachód. Heathrow jest obsługiwane przez ok. 90 linii lotniczych. Lotnisko oferuje regularne połączenia z ponad 90 krajami świata. Heathrow jest jednym z pięciu portów lotniczych obsługujących metropolię londyńską, i jedynym z dwu (oprócz portu City) leżącym na obszarze Wielkiego Londynu, w Hillingdon. Komunikację z portem lotniczym zapewniają autostrady M4 i M25, docierające do terminali linie kolejowe, autobusowe i autokarowe oraz linia metra.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="ko">런던 히드로 공항은 영국 런던에 있는 국제공항이다.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="fi">London Heathrow Airport on Lontoon ja koko Ison-Britannian suurin kansainvälinen lentoasema. Asema sijaitsee Hillingdonin kaupunkipiirissä, 24 kilometriä Lontoon keskustasta länteen. Heathrow on matkustajamääriltään maailman kolmanneksi vilkkain lentoasema ja ulkomaanlennoiltaan maailman vilkkain. Heathrow’n omistaa espanjalaisen Grupo Ferrovialin omistama BAA plc (entinen British Airports Authority). BAA:lle kuuluu myös kuusi muuta lentoasemaa: Gatwick, Stansted, Glasgow, Edinburgh, Aberdeen ja Southampton. Monopoliaseman vuoksi Civil Aviation Authority valvoo tiukasti lentoasemien maksuja. Huhtikuussa 2003 lentoasema veloitti keskimäärin 6,13 puntaa matkustajaa kohden.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="en">London Heathrow Airport or Heathrow is a major airport serving London, England, United Kingdom. Located in the London Borough of Hillingdon, in West London, Heathrow is the busiest airport in the United Kingdom and the third busiest airport in the world (as of 2011) in terms of total passenger traffic, handling more international passengers than any other airport around the globe. It is also the busiest airport in the EU by passenger traffic and the third busiest in Europe given the number of traffic movements, with a figure surpassed only by Paris-Charles de Gaulle Airport and Frankfurt Airport. Heathrow is London's main airport, having replaced RAF Northolt, and together with Gatwick, Southend, Stansted, Luton and London City, London is the busiest city airport system in the world by passenger traffic (with 133,666,888 passengers travelling through the five airports); and second only to New York City in terms of traffic movements. The airport sustains 76,600 jobs directly and around 116,000 indirectly in the immediate area, and this, together with the large number of global corporations with offices close to the airport, makes Heathrow a modern aerotropolis which contributes an estimated 2.7% to London's total GVA. The airport is owned and operated by BAA Limited, who also own and operate five other UK airports. BAA is owned by ADI Limited, an international consortium led by Ferrovial Group, which also includes Caisse de dépôt et placement du Québec and GIC Special Investments. Heathrow is a primary hub for BMI and British Airways as well as a base for Virgin Atlantic Airways. Heathrow lies 12 nautical miles (22 km; 14 mi) west of Central London, and has two parallel east–west runways along with four operational terminals on a site that covers 12.14 square kilometres (4.69 sq mi). Terminal 5 was officially dedicated by Queen Elizabeth II on 14 March 2008 and opened to passengers on 27 March 2008. Construction of a new Terminal 2 complex to replace the old terminal building and adjacent Queen's Building began in 2009 with the first phase expected to open in 2014. Terminals 3 and 4 underwent major refurbishments between 2007–2009. In November 2007, a consultation process began for the building of a new third runway and a sixth terminal, which was controversially approved on 15 January 2009 by UK Government ministers. The project was subsequently cancelled on 12 May 2010 by the Cameron Government. The airport holds a Civil Aviation Authority Public Use Aerodrome Licence (Number P527), which allows flights for public transportation of passengers or for flying instruction.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="vi">Sân bay London Heathrow, được gọi là Heathrow, là sân bay quốc tế tại thủ đô London, là sân bay nhộn nhịp thứ 3 thế giới năm 2005, xếp sau Sân bay Quốc tế Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta và Sân bay Chicago O'Hare. Heathrow, tuy nhiên, phục vụ nhiều khách quốc tế hơn bất kỳ sân bay nào khác. Heathrow là sân bay nhộn nhịp nhất Vương quốc Anh, lớn nhất châu Âu. Sân bay tọa lạc cách Charing Cross 24 km đông Trung tâm London. Sân bay có 2 đường băng chính song song chạy theo hướng đông-tây và 5 nhà nhà ga hành khách. Nhà ga số 5 mới được xây dựng và đang có kế hoạch xây lại và phát triển thêm các nhà ga khác. Năm 2005, sân bay này phục vụ 67,7 triệu khách. Đang có kế hoạch xây thêm đường băng thứ 3. Lúc nhà ga số 5 và đường băng số 3 hoàn thành, sân bay này sẽ có công suất thiết kế 115 triệu khách/năm.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="ru">Хи́троу — крупнейший международный аэропорт Лондона. Считается третьим по загруженности пассажирским аэропортом в мире (2011 год), и первым в Европе. Расположен в 24 км (15 милях) к западу от центрального Лондона. Включает 5 пассажирских терминалов и один грузовой. Последний, 5-й терминал, открыт 14 марта 2008 года королевой Елизаветой II, с 11 апреля 2008 закрывался по техническим причинам до июня 2008 года.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="pt">O Aeroporto de Londres Heathrow, também conhecido como Aeroporto de Heathrow, está localizado a oeste de da cidade de Londres, no do Reino Unido. O Aeroporto de Heathrow é o terceiro mais movimentado do mundo a seguir ao Aeroporto Internacional de Atlanta e ao Aeroporto Internacional O'Hare, de Chicago e é o maior aeroporto do mundo em termos de tráfego de passageiros internacionais. Localizado 24 km a oeste de Londres, Heathrow possui duas pistas paralelas principais, no sentido leste-oeste e cinco terminais, cobrindo uma área de 12,14 qulômetros quadrados. Seu Terminal 5 foi oficialmente inaugurado pela Rainha Elizabeth II em 14 de março de 2008 e aberto aos passageiros no dia 27 do mesmo mês.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="fr">L'aéroport de Londres Heathrow est situé dans la banlieue ouest de Londres au Royaume-Uni. C'est le quatrième aéroport mondial en termes de trafic de passagers, avec environ 65,9 millions qui y ont transité en 2010. Il est le premier aéroport d'Europe en termes de passagers et il est le premier aéroport mondial pour le trafic international, avec plus de 63 millions de passagers internationaux pour les douze mois précédant le 31 mai 2011. En ce qui concerne le nombre de mouvements, l'aéroport ne se classe qu'au 13 rang mondial avec 454 883 décollages/atterrissages, mais est deuxième d'Europe derrière Paris-Charles-de-Gaulle. Il est l'un des 6 aéroports internationaux de Londres et il appartient à BAA Limited qui gère, en plus d'Heathrow, six autres aéroports britanniques (Gatwick, Stansted, Southampton, Glasgow, Aberdeen et Edimbourg). L'aéroport de Londres Heathrow constitue la plate-forme de correspondance principale (hub) pour plusieurs compagnies aériennes britanniques, British Airways, bmi et Virgin Atlantic.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <dbp-ont:abstract xml:lang="it">L'Aeroporto di Londra Heathrow è l'aeroporto principale di Londra. È l'aeroporto più trafficato dell'Unione Europea per numero di passeggeri (e terzo al mondo dopo quelli di Atlanta e Pechino) ed il terzo, nell'UE, per numero di movimenti aerei preceduto da Parigi-Charles de Gaulle e Francoforte; grazie al numero di voli internazionali, è l'aeroporto con il più alto numero di movimenti di passeggeri di voli internazionali. L'aeroporto è dotato di cinque terminal, l'ultimo dei quali, il terminal 5, inaugurato il 15 marzo 2008, viene utilizzato in esclusiva dalla British Airways, la compagnia di bandiera del Regno Unito e può gestire, potenzialmente, 30 milioni di passeggeri l'anno. Il nuovo terminal si distingue per gli elevati standard di qualità e vanta grandi spazi e nuovi servizi.</dbp-ont:abstract>
        <geo-pos:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-0.461389 51.4775)</geo-pos:geometry>
        <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Heathrow_Airport"/>
        <dbp-prop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/London_Heathrow_Airport"/>
        <geo-pos:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">51.4775</geo-pos:lat>
        <dbp-prop:type xml:lang="en">Public</dbp-prop:type>
        <dbp-ont:owner rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BAA_Limited"/>
        <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/02/Heathrow_Airport_logo.png"/>
        <dbp-prop:owner rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BAA_Limited"/>
        <dbp-prop:name xml:lang="en">London Heathrow Airport</dbp-prop:name>
        <dbp-ont:elevation rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#double">25.2984</dbp-ont:elevation>
        <dbp-ont:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/02/Heathrow_Airport_logo.png/200px-Heathrow_Airport_logo.png"/>
        <dbp-prop:longew xml:lang="en">W</dbp-prop:longew>
        <dbp-prop:latm rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">28</dbp-prop:latm>
        <dbp-prop:latns xml:lang="en">N</dbp-prop:latns>
        <dbp-prop:longd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">0</dbp-prop:longd>
        <dbp-prop:longs rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">41</dbp-prop:longs>
        <dbp-prop:longm rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">27</dbp-prop:longm>
        <dbp-prop:lats rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">39</dbp-prop:lats>
        <dbp-prop:latd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">51</dbp-prop:latd>
        <dbp-prop:coordinatesRegion xml:lang="en">GB-HIL</dbp-prop:coordinatesRegion>
        <dbp-prop:website rdf:resource="http://www.heathrowairport.com/"/>
        <dbp-prop:caption rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London_Heathrow_Terminal_5"/>
        <dbp-prop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
        <dbp-prop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London"/>
        <dbp-prop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London_Borough_of_Hillingdon"/>
        <dbp-prop:pushpinMap xml:lang="en">Greater London</dbp-prop:pushpinMap>
        <dbp-ont:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
        <dbp-ont:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London"/>
        <dbp-ont:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London_Borough_of_Hillingdon"/>
        <dbp-prop:footnotes xml:lang="en">Statistics from the UK Civil Aviation Authority</dbp-prop:footnotes>
        <dbp-prop:footnotes xml:lang="en">Sources: UK AIP at NATS and EUROCONTROL</dbp-prop:footnotes>
        <dbp-prop:pushpinMapCaption xml:lang="en">Location within Greater London</dbp-prop:pushpinMapCaption>
        <dbp-prop:image xml:lang="en">Heathrow T5.jpg</dbp-prop:image>
        <dbp-prop:icao xml:lang="en">EGLL</dbp-prop:icao>
        <dbp-prop:iata xml:lang="en">LHR</dbp-prop:iata>
        <dbp-prop:statYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2011</dbp-prop:statYear>
        <dbp-prop:operator xml:lang="en">Heathrow Airport Limited</dbp-prop:operator>
        <dbp-prop:imageWidth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbp-prop:imageWidth>
        <dbp-prop:pushpinLabel xml:lang="en">EGLL</dbp-prop:pushpinLabel>
        <dbp-ont:runwayDesignation xml:lang="en">09L/27R</dbp-ont:runwayDesignation>
        <dbp-ont:runwayDesignation xml:lang="en">09R/27L</dbp-ont:runwayDesignation>
        <dbp-prop:r2Surface xml:lang="en">Grooved asphalt</dbp-prop:r2Surface>
        <dbp-prop:stat2Header xml:lang="en">Passenger change 10-11</dbp-prop:stat2Header>
        <dbp-prop:stat1Data rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">69433230</dbp-prop:stat1Data>
        <dbp-ont:runwayLength rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#double">3660.0</dbp-ont:runwayLength>
        <dbp-ont:runwayLength rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#double">3901.0</dbp-ont:runwayLength>
        <dbp-prop:r2LengthM rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3660</dbp-prop:r2LengthM>
        <dbp-prop:elevationF rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">83</dbp-prop:elevationF>
        <dbp-ont:iataLocationIdentifier xml:lang="en">LHR</dbp-ont:iataLocationIdentifier>
        <dbp-prop:r1Surface xml:lang="en">Grooved Asphalt</dbp-prop:r1Surface>
        <dbp-prop:metricRwy xml:lang="en">yes</dbp-prop:metricRwy>
        <dbp-prop:stat2Data rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5</dbp-prop:stat2Data>
        <dbp-prop:stat3Data rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">480906</dbp-prop:stat3Data>
        <dbp-ont:runwaySurface xml:lang="en">Grooved asphalt</dbp-ont:runwaySurface>
        <dbp-ont:runwaySurface xml:lang="en">Grooved Asphalt</dbp-ont:runwaySurface>
        <dbp-ont:icaoLocationIdentifier xml:lang="en">EGLL</dbp-ont:icaoLocationIdentifier>
        <dbp-prop:image2Width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">280</dbp-prop:image2Width>
        <dbp-prop:wmo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3772</dbp-prop:wmo>
        <dbp-prop:hub rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Airways"/>
        <dbp-prop:stat4Data rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6</dbp-prop:stat4Data>
        <dbp-prop:stat4Header xml:lang="en">Movements change 10-11</dbp-prop:stat4Header>
        <dbp-prop:stat1Header xml:lang="en">Passengers</dbp-prop:stat1Header>
        <dbp-prop:r2Number rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">9</dbp-prop:r2Number>
        <dbp-prop:r1LengthM rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3901</dbp-prop:r1LengthM>
        <dbp-prop:r1Number rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">9</dbp-prop:r1Number>
        <dbp-prop:stat3Header xml:lang="en">Aircraft movements</dbp-prop:stat3Header>
</rdf:Description>

</rdf:RDF>
